Register of the Andrei Terent'evich Bel'chenko Papers, 1898-1962
Hoover Institution Archives
Andrei Terent'evich Bel'chenko Papers
1898-1962
99049
Hoover Institution Archives
34 microfilm reels (5.1 linear feet)
Diaries, speeches and writings, correspondence, consular reports, printed matter, and photographs, relating to Russian and Portuguese relations with China, political conditions in China, and Russian émigré affairs.
Bel'chenko, Andrei Terent'evich, 1873-1958
Access
Collection open for research.
Biography
Russian consular official; consul general, Hankow, China, 1915-1920; subsequently Portuguese consul general, Hankow, and émigré in the United States.
Biographical Note
Andrew T. Bel'tchenko, 1873 - 1958
Andrew Bel'tchenko was born in the village of Kozlovka, Bobrovskii uezd, Voronezhskaiia guberniia, Russia, on 29 October 1873. He graduated from St. Petersburg University with a degree in Oriental philology in 1897. Entering the Foreign Ministry, he was assigned to the Imperial Russian Legation at Peking as a student interpreter in 1899, where he witnessed the Boxer Rebellion and participated in the defense of the diplomatic quarter against the Boxers. Steadily climbing the career ladder, he was commissioned Acting Consul at Foochow in 1901, Vice-Consul at Hankow in 1902, Assistant Secretary of the Russian Legation at Peking in 1903, Consul at Niuchuang (Manchuria) in 1906, Consul at Foochow in 1910, Consul at Canton in 1912, and finally, Consul-General at Hankow in 1915. Andrew T. Bel'tchenko
More than a ministerial functionary, he was an avid student of China throughout his life. In 1912 he translated (into English) I. S. Brunnert's The Present Day Political Organization of China (Shanghai, 1912), and it was his intimate acquaintance with the politics and institutions of that land that saved him from the fate of other Russian diplomats when the Chinese government ceased to recognize their credentials. In 1920 he became advisor to the Chinese government in Hankow on Russian affairs (there was a small but influential Russian colony in Hankow with commercial enterprises), and from 1923 until his departure from China in 1947 he served as Portuguese Consul-General in Hankow, retaining his responsibilities for the Russian colony as well.
The primary value of the collection lies in Bel'tchenko's reports, diaries, scrapbooks, and collected materials on Chinese politics for this period, particularly for 1927, when Hankow became the Nationalist capital. The materials include clippings and issues of rare newspapers, such as the Hankow Herald, North China Daily News, Central China Post, and others, many of which may no longer be extant. In addition, there are significant materials on the Russian and other foreign concessions in Hankow, the Japanese occupation of that region, and Russian émigrés in Hankow and Shanghai, including correspondence, clippings, registration books, legal papers, photographs and other matter.
Following his departure from China, Bel'tchenko went briefly to Paris before settling in San Francisco, where he helped other Russian refugees from China as head of the Obshchestvo pomoshchi russkim na Tubabao and assisted in the work of the Museum of Russian Culture. He died in San Francisco on 1 February 1958.
Biographical Chronology
1873 October 29 (N.S.) Born, Kozlovka village, Bobrovskii uezd, Voronezh guberniia, Russia
1897 Graduated from St. Petersburg University with degree in Oriental philology
1898 Entered Foreign Ministry
1899 Student interpreter, Imperial Russian Legation, Peking
1901 Acting Consul, Foochow
1902 Vice-Consul, Hankow
1903 Assistant Secretary, Imperial Russian Legation in Peking
1906 Consul, Neuchuang (Manchuria)
1910 Consul, Foochow
1912 Translator, Present-Day Political Organization of China
1912 Consul, Canton
1915 Consul-General, Hankow
1920 Adviser to Chinese government on Russian affairs, Hankow
1923 Portuguese Consul-General, Hankow
1947 Left China for United States
1958 February 1 Died, San Francisco
Literary Pseudonyms
A. B.
A. F. G.
Al'fa
Andru
A-Sh
Az-Buki [Azbuki]
Bat-ia
Bat'ko
B-ch
Bol'shevik-teoretik
G-N
Ian'-Shi-Tzia
Iu Chzhi U-tsai [Iu-chizhi u-tsai]
Khan'kovets
Kitaefil
Liubitel' puteshestvii
Obozrevatel'
Odin iz russkikh
Poltavskii Kazak [Poltavskii Kozak]
Starozhil
Tszyrev
Ukhanets
Scope and Content
This collection consists of the papers of the Russian and Portuguese Consul in Hankow, China. The main emphasis is on this city and its surroundings in the period 1918-1946, but there is information on more general developments in China, Russia (the Soviet Union) and the United States over the entire period from 1898 to 1962.
Where possible, the arrangement reflects the original order established by Bel'chenko and respects many of the categories defined by A. S. Loukashkin, who processed the collection upon its acquisition by the Museum of Russian Culture.
A Chinese politics series has been created to encompass materials not readily absorbed into the usual series. This series contains materials relating to Bel'chenko's service as Portuguese Consul in Hankow as well as his continued performance of consular and representative functions with respect to the Russian colony in Hankow and to the Russian émigré diplomatic corps. It includes his consular reports, correspondence, and Bel'chenko's published and unpublished summaries and reports on Chinese political developments, with supporting materials (mainly clippings from the Hankow Herald, Central China Post, China Courier, People's Tribune, Journal de Shanghai, North China Daily News and other newspapers).
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and Museum of Russian Culture. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials and copyright to them (with some exceptions) are the property of the Museum of Russian Culture, San Francisco. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is available at the Hoover Institution Archives.
The Hoover Institution assumes all responsibility for notifying users that they must comply with the copyright law of the United States (Title 17 United States Code) and Hoover Rules for the Use and Reproduction of Archival Materials.
China--Foreign relations--Portugal.; China--Foreign relations--Russia.; China--History--Republic, 1912-1949.; China.; Portugal--Foreign relations--China.; Portugal.; Russia--Foreign relations--China.; Russia.; Russians--United States.; United States.
- Biographical File, 1898-1962; Box 1
  Scope and Contents note
  Autobiographical notes and materials, identity papers, personal papers and other documents reflecting Bel'chenko's diplomatic activities (including materials set aside for the compilation of memoirs), arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Address ], presented to Bel'chenko by the Russian colony of Hankow on the occasion of the 25th anniversary of his diplomatic service, [1923 December 12 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Articles and printed information about A. T. Bel'chenko. Includes issues of The Pioneer, 1919 February and Pela Patria, (with photograph), 1940 July 1 (Folder 2)
  - Autobiographical note on service in China Includes attached copy of service record, (1899-1946). (Folder 3)
  - Biographical note and resume by A. S. Loukashkin (Folder 4)
  - Carta Patente, certifying Bel'chenko as Portuguese Consul in Hankow, signed by Manuel Gomes, President of the Portuguese Republic, and correspondence relating to relinquishing of said post, 1948, 1924 May 9 (Folder 5)
  - Certificate of naturalization (U.S.), Correspondence, 1954 November 11 (Folder 6)
    - Family. Letter to his children, 1928. For letter to son, V. A. Beltchenko, see SPEECHES AND WRITINGS/"Zhatva mira," [1951], 1951 September 10 (Folder 7)
    - Glavnaia kantseliariia russkikh emigrantov v g. Parizhe, 1947 September 29 (Folder 8)
    - United States. Embassy (France), 1947 October 14 (Folder 9)
  - Memoirs ("Zapiski konsula"). Materials set aside for the compilation of Bel'chenko's memoirs. Folder titles reflect arrangement of material by A. S. Loukashkin
    - "A. T. Bel'chenko, kak vybornyi predstavitel' russkoi kolonii v Khan'kou." Consists of minutes of meeting of General Council of Russian citizens of Hankow, and related material, 1927 February 15 (Folder 10)
    - "A. T. Bel'chenko, Sovetnik Kitaiskogo Pravitel'stva v Khan'kou po russkim delam." Includes documents relating to the abolition of Russian Concession in Hankow and its administration by Chinese officials (including photograph of Shen Tze Liang, Chief of Provisional Administrative Bureau), correspondence, regulations, and printed matter, 1922-1925 (Folder 11)
    - "Materialy k biografii A. T. Bel'chenko." Includes addresses, clippings and correspondence reflecting Bel'chenko's diplomatic career in China, Also includes invitations and clippings relating to festivities in honor of the 30th anniversary of Bel'chenko's consular service in China, 1928, 1923-1928. (Folder 12)
    - "Perepiska, bumagi i dokumenty Andreia Terent'evicha Bel'chenko." Includes diary entries, diplomatic and personal correspondence, materials on Chinese politics and materials on Russians and other foreigners in China, particularly Hankow, 1917-1943 (Folder 13)
    - "Russkaia koloniia v Khan'kou." Documents and photographs relating to the establishment and history of the Russian colony in Hankow. Includes correspondence and legal agreements relating to the Kuling and Luling estates near Hankow, 1896-1936 (Folder 14)
  - Passport and identity documents (Russian), Includes photograph, 1898 December 12-1920 September 20. (Folder 15)
  - Service records, [1917]-1920 (Folder 16)
  - Subject file
    - Attack on Bel'chenko in the consulate by unknown assailants, Correspondence, 1927 March - April. (Folder 17)
    - Conflict between Bel'chenko and Japanese military authorities, Correspondence and clipping, 1939 March. (Folder 18)
    - Decorations
      - Correspondence between V. A. Bel'chenko and A. S. Loukashkin relating to A. T. Bel'chenko's medals and decorations. Includes photograph and list of depicted decorations by A. S. Loukashkin, 1962 May 3 - July 15 (Folder 19)
      - Decrees, orders and official correspondence relating to decorations conferred on Bel'chenko by the Russian, Chinese, Italian and French governments, 1900 December 14-1927 June 28 (Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous Chinese documents and identity papers, including notice of safe passage issued to Bel'chenko by Chinese Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 1917-1923 (Folder 21)
- Diaries, 1916-1947.; Boxes 1-9
  Include calling cards, clippings from Russian and English newspapers, correspondence, invitations, menus, photographs, programs and similar enclosures, pasted or freely inserted within text. Arranged chronologically by title. See also BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, SCRAPBOOKS, REGISTRATION FILE, SUBJECT FILE
  - General. Fragments of diary entries, 1916-1925? Includes attached article (clipping) by B. Koliubakin, "Bagdadskaia zheleznaia doroga," Russkii invalid, as well as group photographs of Bel'chenko with unidentified people and photographs of Chinese architecture (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - See SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1917 March-April.
  - Includes clippings on situation in Russia and China from November 1917, 1918 January 18 - February 28. (Folder 23)
  - 1918 May 3 - June 10 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 1918 July 10 - July 21 (Folder 2)
  - 1930 September 1 - November 30 (Folder 3)
  - 1930 December 4-1931 December 14 (Folder 4)
  - 1931 January 1-1932 January 5 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1932 January 6 - May 20 (Folder 2)
  - 1932 May 21 - October 29 (Folder 3)
  - 1932 November 1-1933 April 30 (Folder 4)
  - 1933 May 1 - October 27 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 1933 October 28-1934 April 14 (Folder 2)
  - 1934 April 17 - November 17 (Folder 3)
  - 1934 November 18-1935 July 2 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 1935 July 3-1936 March 1 (Folder 2)
  - 1936 March 4-1936 November 17 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - 1936 November 18-1937 February 25 (Folder 2)
  - 1937 February 26 - October 20 (Folder 3)
  - 1937 October 22-1938 June 23 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - 1938 June 24-1939 January 10 (Folder 2)
  - 1939 January 11 - December 31 (Folder 3)
  - 1940 January 1 - June 1 (Folder 4)
  - 1940 June 2-1941 January 1 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 1941 January 2 - December 2 (Folder 2)
  - 1941 December 2-1942 February 10 (Folder 3)
  - 1942 February 11 - December 31 (Folder 4)
  - 1943 January 1 - December 31 (Folder 5)
  - Includes entries and clippings from 1943, 1944 January 1-1944 December 9. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - See OVERSIZE FILE, 1944 December 10-1945 October 30.
  - 1945 October 30-1946 June 19 (Folder 2)
  - 1946 June 20 - December 20 (Folder 3)
  - 1946 December 21-1947 February 3 (Folder 4)
  - 1947 February 4 - November 21 (Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1916-1957.; Box 9
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent. See also BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, DIARIES, SCRAPBOOKS, REGISTRATION FILE, CHINESE POLITICS FILE, SUBJECT FILE
  - General (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Unidentified [Egor Antonovich], 1930 (Folder 7)
  - Boldyrev, V., 1920 (Folder 8)
  - Grosse, Viktor Fedorovich, 1920-1921 (Folder 9)
  - Gutman [Gan], A., 1920 (Folder 10)
  - Ivanov, N. A., 1925-1926 (Folder 11)
  - Korostovets, I. Ia., 1922 (Folder 12)
  - Liubimova, N., 1937 (Folder 13)
  - Melnikoff, D. M., 1938 (Folder 14)
  - Metsler, K. [Metzler, Charles], 1916 (Folder 15)
  - Mills, E., 1929 (Folder 16)
  - Noskoff, Constantin, n.d. (Folder 17)
  - Shang S. S., 1922 (Folder 18)
  - Sihvonen, E. Includes letter from M. Meedar, 1920, 1921. (Folder 19)
  - Soiuz Vostochnikov, Kharbinskii Otdel, Includes clipping about K. V. Lovtsov, 1935, 1918. (Folder 20)
  - Ter-Oganesov, S., 1930-1932 (Folder 21)
  - Uvarov, Boris Grigor'evich, 1941 (Folder 22)
  - Vaskevich, Pavel Iur'evich, 1957 (Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous undated fragments of correspondence, possibly from V. O. von Klemm and B. V. Ostroumov (Folder 24)
- Speeches And Writings, 1912-1951.; Boxes 9-10
  Articles, speeches and drafts of works, arranged chronologically by title. For Bel'chenko's published reports on Chinese political developments, see CHINESE POLITICS FILE/Reports/"Politicheskie sobytiia v Kitae"
  - General
    - General (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Clippings of newspaper articles, mainly from Russkaia zhizn', Includes background materials and notes, 1947-1949. (Folder 26)
    - Fragments. Articles, and correspondence relating to their publication, 1948 (Folder 27)
    - Materials assembled by A. S. Loukashkin
      - "Andrei Terent'evich Bel'chenko: Ego gazetnye i zhurnalnye stat'i," 1912-1950. Consists mainly of clippings of Bel'chenko's articles from various newspapers, some drafts and background material, correspondence with L. V. Arnol'dov regarding publication in the newspaper Shankhaiskaia zaria, and with V. A. Maklakov regarding political developments in China, 1939, 1942-1943 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - "Andrei Terent'evich Bel'chenko: Ego stat'i v gazetakh i zhurnalakh," 1921-1950. Consists mainly of clippings of Bel'chenko's articles from various newspapers, some drafts and background materials. Most articles form a series of correspondences entitled "Sobytiia v Khan'kou" or "Pis'mo iz Khan'kou," 1927-1937. Includes correspondence with P. I. Zaitsev regarding their publication in the newspaper Slovo, 1932, and V. F. Zeeler regarding the newspaper Russkaia mysl', 1948-1950 (Folder 2)
  - "Istoriia obrazovaniia v Kitae," Holograph and typescript (Folder 3)
  - "Kak vy mozhete predokhranit' sebia ot vzryva atomnoi bomby," Typescript, n.d. (Folder 4)
  - "Kazaki (Istoricheskii ocherk)," Holograph, n.d. (Folder 5)
  - "Ocherki po bol'shevizmu v Kitae," Holograph and typescript (Folder 6)
  - "Taina samoubiistva Ioffe," See OVERSIZE FILE, n.d.
  - "Triumf 'Narodnoi demokratii' na stsene Moskvy," n.d. Typescript. Typed on the back of diary entries for, 1917 March-April (Folder 7)
  - "Iz pisem russkogo puteshestvennika," Izvestiia Soveta russkoi kontsessii v Khan'kou, Printed copy, 1918. (Folder 8)
  - Speech given on the beginning of construction of a new Russian School in Hankow, Typescript. Includes school program, 1918 September 12. (Folder 9)
  - "Zametki o Khubeiskom tsementnom zavode Obshchestva 'Khua-Tszi'," Typescript. Includes "L'industrie siderurgique et metallurgique en Chine," n.d. Typescript (possibly also by Bel'chenko or used as background material), 1918 September 18. (Folder 10)
  - "Chainye plantatsii v Kitae," Typescript. Includes photographs, 1918 September 27. (Folder 11)
  - "Poezdka iz Khan'kou v Fuchzhou, glavnyi gorod provintsii Futszian', sukhim putem cherez provintsiiu Tziansi," Typescript, 1918 December 26. (Folder 12)
  - Ocherk politicheskoi zhizni Kitaia v 1918 godu, Harbin, Printed copy, 1919. (Folder 13)
  - "Ocherk chainoi torgovli v Khan'kou, K'iukiane i Shankhae v 1918 godu," Typescript, 1919 March 1. (Folder 14)
  - "Missiia A. A. Ioffe i professor A. I. Ivanov," Sviet, Printed copy, 1922 August 31. (Folder 15)
  - Untitled work on Metropolitan Arsenii of Rostov, Holograph, 1938 January 8. (Folder 16)
  - "Sovetskie deiateli i inostrantsy," Shankhaiskaia zaria, 1942 August 9-11. Printed copy. Includes typescript entitled "Bol'sheviki i inostrantsy" and correspondence with the editor of Shankhaiskaia zaria, L. V. Arnol'dov (Folder 17)
  - "Pervye russkie v Kitae posle vosstaniia bokserov," Holograph, 1942 August 19-24. (Folder 18)
  - "Chto eto - prestuplenie?" Holograph, [1947]. (Folder 19)
  - "Naivnost', nevezhestvo ili neponimanie," Typescript, 1947 August. (Folder 20)
  - "Vpechatleniia ot russkogo Parizha," Russkaia zhizn', Typescript draft and printed copy, 1947 August 8. (Folder 21)
  - "Oni izbrali svobodu,", 1947 November 3 (Folder 22)
  - "Pervye vpechatleniia ot Ameriki," Typescript and correspondence, 1948 February 20. (Folder 23)
  - "Villard Streit - Mikhail Streit - Genri Uolles," Typescript, 1948 May 5. (Folder 24)
  - "Genri Uolles i 3-ia politicheskaia partiia v Soedinennykh shtatakh," Includes correspondence, 1948 July 24. (Folder 25)
  - "O russkoi pechati v g. Khan'kou." See SUBJECT FILE
  - "Tridsat' vtoraia godovshchina sovetskoi vlasti," ]. Typescript and correspondence, [1949 November (Folder 26)
  - "Vneshniaia sovetskaia politika," Typescript and printed copy, 1949 November 17-30. (Folder 27)
  - "Zhatva mira," [1951]. Background material and typescript. Reverse side contains letter to son, V. A. Bel'chenko, 1951 September 10 (Folder 28)
  - "Moral'noe perevooruzhenie," Typescript and correspondence, 1951 October. (Folder 29)
- Scrapbooks, 1890-1954.; Boxes 11-13
  Include clippings, calling cards, greeting cards and correspondence, event programs, menus, photographs and notes. In many cases the subjects covered go beyond the titles of the scrapbooks. Arranged chronologically. See also REGISTRATION FILE, SUBJECT FILE
  - "Zhizn' v Ostrogorske, Peterburge, Pekine, Fuchzhou, Khan'kou, g.g.", 1890-1902 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - "Iuridicheskie formy i izveshcheniia,", [c. 1901]-1954 (Folder 2)
  - "Zhizn' v Pekine, ", 1904-1905 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - "Zhizn' v Niuchzhuane i Peterburge ", (1906-1909) (Folder 2)
  - "Pozdravleniia, priglasheniia i t.p. s 24-go dekabria g. po konets noiabria 1929 g.", 1928 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - "Razlichnye programmy, priglasheniia I tomu podobnye zametki i zapiski za vremia s noiabria goda po fevral' 1930 goda vkliuchitel'no", 1929 (Folder 2)
  - Untitled, 1938-1941 (Folder 3)
  - Untitled, Consists mainly of bibliographic references, notes and opinions of books relating to Russia and the U.S.S.R., 1945-1952. (Folder 4)
  - "Arkhiepiskop Viktor i kharbintsy,", 1946 July-1947 July (Folder 5)
- Registration File, 1922-1944.; Boxes 14-16
  Lists, forms and questionnaires, with photographs, biographical details, correspondence and other matter relating to their livelihoods and activities. Includes material of scrapbook nature and diary entries, arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Lists
    - General, (alphabetical list), 1932-1937 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - "List of White Russians in Hankow,", 1939 February 20 (Folder 2)
  - Registration forms, [1939]
    - General
      - A-Z (Folder 3)
      - I-M (Folder 4)
      - N-S (Folder 5)
      - T-Ia (Folder 6)
    - Departed and deceased
      - A-Ia (without recommendations) (Folder 7)
      - A-Ia (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - K-S (Folder 2)
  - Registration questionnaires, n.d. (Folder 3)
  - Scrapbooks. Also contain general scrapbook material
    - 1922-1942 (Folder 4)
    - 1924-1944 (Folder 5)
    - 1931-1935 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Chinese Politics File, 1918-1949.; Boxes 16-22
  Correspondence, printed matter, notes and reports, arranged alphabetically by physical form. Includes Bel'chenko's reports to Senior Russian Diplomatic Representative Abroad on political developments in China, as well as published versions of those reports in Russian periodicals in China (under the author's pseudonyms, in Russkoe ekho, Slovo, Russkoe slovo, Armiia i flot). Also includes background materials (mainly clippings used in the compilation of the reports). See also BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, SCRAPBOOKS, SUBJECT FILE
  - Consular reports - Portugal. Reports and drafts of reports to Portuguese Envoy Extraordinaire and Minister Plenipotentiary A. de Bianchi, Portuguese Ministers to China Armando Navarro and Joao de Lebre e Lima and charges d'affaires of the Portuguese Legation. Include clippings, calling cards, invitations and related material appended to reports
    - Undated fragments (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - 1926 April 4-1937 December 3 (Folder 3)
    - 1939 January 31-1943 June 21 (Folder 4)
  - Correspondence
    - France. Consulat (Han-k'ou), 1924-1927 (Folder 5)
    - Kudashev, Nikolai A., Prince, 1918 (Folder 6)
    - Maklakov, Vasilii Alekseevich, 1938-1939 (Folder 7)
  - Notebook of citations from Chinese newspapers, Also includes notes, quotes, clippings, and bibliographic citations, 1916 and 1949, 1900 July-August. (Folder 8)
  - Notes
    - General, 1927 (Folder 9)
    - On leading Chinese political and military figures (Folder 10)
  - Quotes from books on Chinese history and politics (Folder 11)
  - Reports - "Politicheskie sobytiia v Kitae"
    - 1921 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - 1922 (Folder 2)
    - - "Report on the Political Situation in Szechuan for 1923" (Folder 3)
    - 1925 (Folder 4)
    - 1926 (Folder 5)
    - 1927 (Folder 6)
    - Attached clippings, 1927 January-July. (Folder 7)
    - Attached clippings, 1927 January-July. (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Attached clippings, 1927 October-December. (Folder 2)
    - Attached clippings on Hankow and the surrounding region, 1927 October-1928 May. (Folder 3)
    - 1928 (Folder 4)
    - Attached clippings, 1928. (Folder 5)
    - Attached clippings on Hankow and the surrounding region, 1928 May-1929 March. (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - 1929 (Folder 2)
    - Printed copy, 1929. (Folder 3)
    - Clippings, 1929. (Folder 4)
    - 1930 (Folder 5)
    - Clippings, 1930. (Folder 6)
    - 1931 (Folder 7)
    - Clippings, 1931. (Folder 8)
    - 1932 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - 1933 (Folder 2)
    - 1934 (Folder 3)
    - 1935 (Folder 4)
    - 1936 (Folder 5)
    - 1937 (Folder 6)
    - 1938 (Folder 7)
    - 1939 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - 1940 (Folder 2)
    - 1941 (Folder 3)
    - 1942 (Folder 4)
    - 1943 (Folder 5)
    - 1944 (Folder 6)
  - Printed matter. Includes Tyau, M. T. Z., ed., China in 1918, Peking, 1919; issues of The Pioneer, Peking, 1919; Société des Nations, Appel du gouvernement chinois: Rapport de la Commission d'étude, Genève, 1932; issues of the Information Bulletin, Nanking, 1936 (Folder 7-8)